(Guitar music)
(موسيقى غيتار)
I was just thinking
كنت أفكر فحسب
that I have been missing you way too long
أني كنت مشتاقًا إليك جداً
There's something inside this weary head
هناك شيء داخل هذا الرأس القلق
that wants us to love just instead
يريد منا أن نحب فقط
But I was just thinking,
لكني كنت فقط أفكر،
merely thinking
مجرد تفكير
I've got loads of pictures,
لدي الكثير من الصور،
I've got the one of you in that dancing dress
لدي واحدة لك في ثوب الرقص
But man I feel silly in that dim light
لكنني أشعر أني سخيف أيها الرجل في هذا الضوء الخافت
Just after doing you by the sight of my Kodak delights,
مباشرة بعد تصويرك بكاميرتي الكوداك،
I am sinking,
إني أغوص،
merely sinking
مجرد غوص
I think about long distance rates instead of kissing you babe
أفكر في المسافات الطويلة بدلاً من تقبيلك حبيبتي
I'm a singer without a song
أنا مغن بدون أغنية
If I wait for you longer
إذا انتظرتك أكثر
my affection is stronger
ستقوى عاطفتي
and I ... I was just thinking,
و أنا..كنت أفكر فحسب،
merely thinking
مجرد تفكير
that this boat is sinking
أن هذا القارب يغرق
I'm tired of postcards,
لقد ضقت ذرعاً بالبطاقات البريدية،
especially the ones with cute dogs and cupids
خصوصاً تلك التي عليها كلاب جميلة و مجموعة من الكيوبيد
I'm tired of calling you and missing you
لقد تعبت من حبك و من الاشتياق إليك
and dreaming I slept with you
و نمت حالماً بك
Don't get me wrong I still desperately love you
لا تفهميني خطأ فأنا لازلت أحبك بيأس
inside this weary head
داخل هذا الرأس القلق
I just want us to love just instead
كنت أريد فقط أن نحب بعضنا
But I was just thinking and thinking,
لكنني كنت أفكر و أفكر،
merely thinking
مجرد تفكير
I think about long distance rates instead of kissing you babe
أفكر في المسافات الطويلة بدلاً من تقبيلك حبيبتي
and time is running me still
و ما زال الوقت يضيع مني
If I wait for you longer
و إن انتظرتك أكثر
my affection is stronger
ستقوى عاطفتي
I ... I was just thinking
أنا..أنا كنت أفكر
that I'm tired of calling you once a week
أني قد ضقت ذرعاً بالاتصال بك مرة واحدة أسبوعياً
thinking of long distance rates instead of kissing you
أفكر في المسافات الطويلة بدلاً من تقبيلك حبيبتي
So baby I'm sinking,
لذلك إنني أغوص يا حبيبتي،
merely sinking
مجرد غوص
(Guitar music ends)
(انتهاء موسيقى الغيتار)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
Singing is sharing.
الغناء هو مشاركة.
When you sing, you have to know what you're talking about intimately,
عندما تغني فعليك معرفة ما تتكلم عنه معرفة وثيقة،
and you have to be willing to share this insight
وعليك أن تكون على استعداد لمشاركة هذه المعرفة
and give away a piece of yourself.
و تعطي قطعة منك.
I look for this intention to share in everything,
أنا أبحث عن النية بالمشاركة في كل شيء،
and I ask: what are the intentions behind this architecture or this product
وأسأل: ما هي النية من وراء هذه العمارة أو هذا المنتج
or this restaurant or this meal?
أو هذا المطعم أو هذه الوجبة؟
And if your intentions are to impress people
وإن كانت نواياك هي إبهار الناس
or to get the big applause at the end,
أو أن تحصل على تصفيق كبير عند النهاية،
then you are taking, not giving.
فإنك تأخذ و لا تعطي.
And this is a song that's about --
و ها هي أغنية عن --
it's the kind of song that everyone has their version of.
إنها أغنية لها نسختها الخاصة عند كل منا.
This song is called "Home,"
تدعى هذه الأغنية "الوطن"
and it's sort of a "This is where I'm from, nice to meet you all,"
و هي نوعاً ما نحو "أتيت من هذا المكان وأنا سعيد في التعرف عليكم جميعاً،"
kind of song.
هذا النوع من الأغاني.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Piano music)
(موسيقى بيانو)
Home is the sound of birds early in the morning
الوطن هو أغنية العصافير في الصباح الباكر
Home is a song I've always remembered
الوطن هو أغنية أتذكرها دائماً
Home is the memory of my first day in school
الوطن هو ذكراي الأولى لأول يوم لي في المدرسة
Home is the books that I carry around
الوطن هو الكتب التي أحملها في طريقي
Home is an alley in a faraway town
الوطن هو جادة في بلدة بعيدة جداً
Home is the places I’ve been and where I’d like to go
الوطن هو الأماكن التي كنت فيها و الأماكن التي أود الذهاب اليها
Home
الوطن
I'm always gonna feel at home
سأشعر دائما بالوطن
No matter where I may roam
غير عابيء بأماكن تجوالي
I'm always gonna find my way back home
سأجد دائما طريق عودتي إلى الوطن
No matter how far I’m gone
غير مكترث بالابتعاد
I’m always gonna feel this longing
سأشعر دائما بهذا التوق
No matter where I might stay
غير مكترث بمكان إقامتي
Home is a feather twirling in the air
الوطن ريشة تدور في الهواء
Home is flowers in a windowsill
الوطن زهرة على حافة النافذة
Home is all the things she said to me
الوطن هو كل الأشياء التي قالتها لي
Home is a photo I never threw away
الوطن صورة لن أرمي بها بعيدا
Home is the smile on my face when I die
الوطن بسمة على وجهي عندما أموت
Home is the taste of an apple pie
الوطن هو مذاق فطيرة التفاح
I met a woman, she always lived in the same place
قابلت امرأة، عاشت طوال حياتها في نفس المكان
And she said home is where you’re born and raised
فقالت أن الوطن هو مكان ولادتك و نشأتك
And I met a man, he sat looking out to the sea
و قابلت رجلا جالسًا يتأمل البحر
And he said home is where you want to be
فقال لي: الوطن هو المكان الذي تود أن تكون فيه
I met a girl in some downtown bar
قابلت فتاة في ملهى ليلي وسط البلدة
And she said I'll have whatever he's having
فقالت سأتناول ما يتناوله
And I asked her how come we never met before?
و سألتها كيف لنا أن لم نلتق قبلاً؟
And she said all my life I’ve been trying
فقالت: طوال حياتي كنت أحاول
to get a place of my own
الحصول على مكان خاص بي
I’m always gonna feel at home
سأشعر دائما كأني في الوطن
No matter where I may roam
غير عابيء بأماكن تجوالي
Always gonna find my way back home
سأجد دائما طريقي إلى الوطن
No matter how far I’m gone
مهما ابتعدت
I'm always gonna feel this longing
سأشعر دائما بهذا الشوق
No matter where I might stay
غير عابيء بمكان إقامتي
(Piano music)
(موسيقى بيانو)
(Piano music ends)
(انتهاء موسيقى البيانو)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)